<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kubernetes on Toasting so much toast</title>
    <link>https://blog.frenchtoastman.com/tags/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kubernetes on Toasting so much toast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Tyler French</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 09:32:37 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.frenchtoastman.com/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>testingdeployment</title>
      <link>https://blog.frenchtoastman.com/posts/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 09:32:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.frenchtoastman.com/posts/testing/</guid>
      <description>Automated Testing Now its time for something fun, this post is going to be taking the ideas from the previous post and giving you all an example of how they can be applied. We are going to be building out test nodes in our vCD environment, built from an valid image for running kubernetes, then taking our backups we have in our etcd gitlab repo and restoring our cluster to these new nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>buildingthething</title>
      <link>https://blog.frenchtoastman.com/posts/building/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 09:32:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.frenchtoastman.com/posts/building/</guid>
      <description>Building something in CI/CD In this post im am going to start exploring what all can be done with CI/CD pipelines in reguards to Kubernetes. So most people have been using CI/CD to deploy out their applications or modify their application that is running to fix a bug or address some feature request. But what can us infrastructure guys do with this? Well everyone seems to preach these days the infrastructure as code right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cicdallthethings</title>
      <link>https://blog.frenchtoastman.com/posts/cicdallthethings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 09:32:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.frenchtoastman.com/posts/cicdallthethings/</guid>
      <description>The Setup This article is about how to configure our Rancher test ENV.
WTF Am i doing? This is what I want to have setup here:
 Rancher RKE Deployment in AWS with ETCD snapshots enabled writing to /opt/rke/snapshots Gitlab single node instance running on the cluster Turns out we have to scp it off the host first then do the rest on the bastin host Git init /opt/rke/snapshots as a repo etcd-snapshots Create cron job that runs:  git add .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>